### Contact

+8801835852526 (Mobile) aklajim3@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ akhlakhossainjim (LinkedIn) akhlak-hossain-jim.github.io/ (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

Web Development
Front-end Development
Leadership

### Languages

Hindi (Limited Working)
English (Professional Working)
Bangla (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Develop your career plan
Start the UX Design Process:
Empathize, Define,and Ideate
The Art Of Public speaking
Learn How to Learn
Create Modern CSS Animations

### Honors-Awards

Semi Finalist (CTTC-DCDS INTER COLLEGE NATIONAL DEBATE TOURNAMENT-2019)

Champion (Evaly-JUDO National Debate Festival 2020)

Runners up (3rd GSSDC National Debate Fest 2020)

## Akhlak Hossain Jim

Front-End Developer | Traveler | Curious Soul Dhaka

### Summary

I'm a self-thought Front-end Developer with 2 years of experience with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS, Styled-Components, and React.js.

UX designer(learning). I'm passionate about Human interaction and Psychology. I'm hungry to learn new things and from every single setback.

In my personal life, I look at things and try to analyze them to solve or think, how that could be different in a positive way and what I can learn from it. I've worked on different kinds of projects, small to large challenging projects to embrace my skills. No matter what I do, I am very invested. And in every moment, I'm growing.

### Experience

AlphaProMed
Frontend Developer
August 2021 - Present (4 months)
Remote

- 1. Convert Wireframe/Mockup to actual design with "pixel perfect" accuracy
- 2. Optimize applications for maximum speed
- 3. Determining the structure and design of web pages
- 4. Design mobile-based features
- 5. Ensuring user experience determines design choices
- 6. Design and developed responsive design for all the resolutions
- 7. Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve the usability
- 8. Write functional requirement documents and guides
- 9. Building reusable code for future use
- 10. Utilizing a variety of markup languages to write web pages
- 11. Create quality mockups and prototypes

- 12. Understand client/owner requirements and implement as same as in the requirement
- 13. Help back-end developers with coding and troubleshooting
- 14. Maintaining brand consistency throughout the design.
- 15. Ensure high-quality graphic standards and brand consistency
- 16. Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies

# Woman Opportunities Frontend Developer February 2021 - Present (10 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- > Modern prototype designing for both user-friendly and easy to use
- > Writing cleanly reusable with modern javascript library React.js
- > Using modern CSS precompiler (S)CSS

# Dhaka Commerce College Debating Society Debater

September 2019 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Bangladesh

Debating in Bot	h Asian and	British	Parliamentary	in B	angla &	English

☐ Helping junior debaters to grow and in their debate careers.

#### Awards:

- ☐ Runners up (3rd GSSDC National Debate Fest 2020)
- ☐ Champion (Evaly-JUDO National Debate Festival 2020)

### AamarTaka.com

### Frontend Developer

June 2021 - August 2021 (3 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- > Modern prototype designing for both user-friendly and easy to use
- > Writing cleanly reusable with modern javascript library React.js, Next.js framework, and integrating APIs
- > Using modern CSS precompiler (S)CSS

### Bangladesh Associates of IT Solution

Sr. Executive, Software and Web developer

January 2021 - January 2021 (1 month)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- > Writing cleanly reusable Front-end code with HTML, (S)CSS, JavaScript
- > Collaborating with other team meats and with the UI team.

### **PARTHIB Associates**

Frontend Developer

November 2020 - December 2020 (2 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- > Modern prototype designing for both user-friendly and easy to use.
- > Writing cleanly reusable with Html, CSS, Bootstrap, and Javascript
- > Using modern CSS precompiler (S)CSS

### Shuvro Jaya

Tech Lead

October 2019 - October 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

As a small company, I covered a variety of areas including,

- ➤ Online presence management
- ➤ Creating internal web applications for dedicated tasks with Reactjs, (S)CSS, Styled-Components
- >> Public Relations through Facebook Messenger
- > Customer Support
- > Marketing strategist

### **DAGMC**

Co-Founder & Organizing Director January 2017 - June 2019 (2 years 6 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

I worked at DAGMC, an institutional organization focused on communication skill development opportunities for every student.

- Co-founder | Organizing Director | Trainer
   From January 2017- June 2019
- 1st GMMSC National Podium 2019 | Chief Organizer
- 3, 4&5 April 2019
- GMMSC Podium 2018 | Organizer
   28 & 30 October 2018

☐ Debated in Both Asian and British Parliamentary in Bangla.
☐ Helped junior debaters to grow and in their debate careers.
☐ Organized one Intra and one National Debate festival.

### Education

Dhaka Commerce College HSC, science · (2019 - 2021)

Mohammadpur model school and college SSC, science · (2016 - 2019)